Finding Aid for the Edouard Roditi Papers LSC.0644
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Correspondence.
  - University of California, Berkeley. Berkeley, Calif., 1939-1940, n.d. (Box 17)
    Re Edouard Roditi's appointment as teaching assistant for the department of French at University of California, Berkeley.
  - University of California, Santa Cruz. Santa Cruz, Calif., 1870.; [1 of 2 folders] (Box 17)
    Also: Hitch, Charles J; McHenry, Dean
    Includes D. McHenry's letter, 17 February 1970, to J. Axelrod; McHenry's letter, 3 April 1970, to Roditi; typescript(carbon) of Roditi's two letters, 26 April 1970 & 14 May 1970, to Charles Hitch and of Roditi's letter, 1 June 1970, to James Hall.
  - University of California, Santa Cruz. Santa Cruz, Calif., 1970-1971.; [2 of 2 folders] (Box 17)
    Also: Putter, Irving; Hall, James
    Typescript(carbon) of Roditi's two letters, 24 July & 24 August 1970, to James Hall and of Roditi's one letter, 24 August 1970, to Irving Putter. One item is an acknowledgment from the UC Santa Cruz library for Roditi's gift.
  - University of Chicago. Chicago., 1940-1960. (Box 17)
    Also: Stauffer, Thomas; McKeon, Richard
    Edouard Roditi's submission to the publication. One letter, 3 June 1960, is from Richard McKeon to Thomas Stauffer.
  - University of Illinois, Urbana. Urbana, Illinois., 1942-1952. (Box 17)
    Discussion on Roditi's articles, "On Books Which Have Remained Abroad," and "The Novels of Post-War Germany."
  - University of Michigan. Ann Arbor, Michigan., 1947. (Box 17)
    Re the reprint of Edouard Roditi's article, "Breviario de amor".
  - University of Minnesota. Minneapolis, Minnesota., 1967. (Box 17)
    Also: Ervin, John Jr.
    Re invitation to write on Nabokov. Roditi's holograph notes are on the back of this letter.
  - University of Oklahoma. Norman, Oklahoma., 1950. (Box 17)
    Also: Poston, Lawrence Jr.
    Re a possible visiting professorship at the University of Oklahoma.
  - University of Washington, Seattle. Seattle, Washington., 1941-1975. (Box 17)
    Also: Modern Language Quarterly. Seattle Washington.; Nostrand, Howard Lee
  - Usborne, Richard., 1981-1983. (Box 17)
    Typescript(carbon) of Edouard Roditi's letter, 9 August 1983, to Richard Usborne is included.
  - Valiquette, Bernard., 1942-1946. (Box 17)
    Enclosed with Bernard Valiquette's original letter, 8 April 1946, are typescript(carbon) of this original letter and a contract for Roditi's book, Souvenir de Paris.; Editions Bernard Valiquette Limited. Montreal.
    These letters are in French. One postcard is included.
  - Van Dyke, Henry., 1966-1984, n.d. (Box 17)
    One letter is undated. Two postcards are included. Re a variety of literary topics.
  - Van Moppes, Denise., 1940. n.d. (Box 17)
    Eight letters are undated. These letters are in French.
  - Van Vechten, Carl., 1942-1953. (Box 17)
  - Varsavsky, Vladimir., 1974. (Box 17)
  - Velloudios., 1977-1978. (Box 17)
    One item has photocopy of Velloudios' poems in English and Greek and of a poetry book cover of "A distant fluttering" by Christopher Towers.
    With 2 postcards.
  - Vendredi. Paris., 1936. (Box 17)
  - Verschoyle, Derek., 1935. (Box 17)
    Also: Spectator. London.
  - Vigee, Claude., 1952. (Box 17)
    One item is a postcard. These letters are in French. Typescript(carbon) of Edouard Roditi's letter, 30 June 1952, to Claude Vigee is included.
  - Viking Press. New York., 1933. (Box 17)
    Also: Oppenheimer, George
  - Vincent, Bernard., 1976-1981. (Box 17)
    Also: Chentier, Marc; Centre d'Etudes et de Recherches sur la Culture Anglo-Americaine. Orleans.
    These letters are in French. Marc Chenetier's letters, 1 September 1978 & 8 May 1981, are addressed to his colleagues. Bernard Vincent's letter to Roditi is written on Marc Chenetier's letter of 8 May 1981.
  - Virginia Quarterly Review. Charlottesville, Virginia., 1944-1950. (Box 17)
    Also: Kohler, Charlotte
  - Vittorini, Elio., 1952. (Box 17)
  - Voila. Paris., 1925-1937. (Box 17)
    Also: Fels, Florent; Gelis
  - Voronca, Ilarie., 1941. (Box 17)
  - Wagner, Ben., 1969. (Box 17)
    Also: Galerie Verlag. Berlin.
  - Wagstaff, Sam., 1983. (Box 17)
  - Waisler, Lee., 1975. (Box 17)
  - Waldberg, Patrick., 1968. (Box 17)
  - Wallis, Eleanor., 1944. (Box 17)
  - Wallis, Robert., 1962. (Box 17)
    Discussion on Edouard Roditi's book on homosexuality.
  - Walter, F., 1976. (Box 17)
  - Warburg, M. M. & Co. Hamburg., 1939. (Box 17)
  - Watkins, Ann Inc. New York., 1950. (Box 17)
    Also: Watkins, Armitage
    Possible book on Germany by Edouard Roditi.
  - Watson, Peter., 1947, n.d. (Box 17)
    Also: Horizon. London.
  - Way, Robert., 1981. (Box 17)
  - Weber, Max., 1959. (Box 17)
  - Weil, Ernst., 1960. (Box 17)
    This letter with a black pen sketch is in French.
  - Weiss, Theodore., 1944-1968. (Box 17)
  - Weissbort, Daniel., 1977. (Box 17)
  - Wells, Herbert George., 1938. (Box 17)
    Also: Blair, Eric
    This letter is from H. G. Wells to Madame Roditi.
  - Western Review. Iowa., n.d. (Box 17)
  - White, Eric Walter., 1936. (Box 17)
    Edouard Roditi's submission of poems to the publication.
  - White, Gary., 1984. (Box 17)
    Also: Maurice F. Neville & Rare Books. Santa Barbara.
  - White, Todd., n.d. (Box 17)
  - Who's Who in World Jewry. New York., 1980. (Box 17)
    Enclosed with I. B. Segal's letter, October 1980, is an another letter from I. B. Segal to subjects of "Who's Who in World Jewry" and typescript(carbon) of Edouard Roditi's short description of his studies of medieval literatures and philosophy.; Segal, I. B.
  - Wiater, Michael., n.d. (Box 17)
    Also: Toothpick, Lisbon & The Orcas Islands. Seattle.
  - Wilder, Thornton., 1952. (Box 17)
    Typescript(carbon) of Edouard Roditi's letter, 26 June 1952, to Thornton Wilder is included.
  - Wileman, David., 1973. (Box 17)
    Re Edouard Roditi's articles concerning "Magellan of the Pacific".
  - Williams, Gil., 1983. (Box 17)
  - Wilson, Edmund., 1944. (Box 17)
    Discussion on Evelyn Waugh's works.
  - Witonski, Peter P., 1977. (Box 17)
  - Wolfe, Humbert., 1936. (Box 17)
  - Wolfskehl, Karl., 1932-1934, n.d. (Box 17)
    One item is undated. One item has two different typescript(carbon) of Wolfskehls's poem, "An Ariel Bension". These letters are in German.
  - Woodcock, George. (Box 17)
    Discussion on Edouard Roditi's book, "Magellan of the Pacific".
  - Woods, Eddie., 1980. (Box 17)
    Also: Ins & Outs Press. Amsterdam.
  - Wunderlich, Paul., 1967-1971. (Box 17)
  - Wynick, Annie., n.d. (Box 17)
    Annie Wynick is the sister of the poet Isaac Rosenberg.
  - Wolf, Robert Erich., 1980-1986. (Box 18)
  - Women Artists News. New York., 1978-1979. (Box 18)
    Also: Arndt, Jennifer
  - Woods, Gregory., 1988. (Box 18)
  - World Jewry. London., 1964. (Box 18)
    Also: Goldsmith, S.J.
  - World Literature Today. University of Oklahoma. Norman, Oklahoma., 1979-1983.; [1 of 3 folders] (Box 18)
    Also: Riggan, William
    With WLT's letter of 8/19/83 is ER's review of NUEVE PROSAS EJEMPLARES by Leonardo de Arrizabalaga y Prado.; Ivask, Ivar
  - World Literature Today. University of Oklahoma. Norman, Oklahoma., 1984-1986.; [2 of 3 folders] (Box 18)
    With ER's letter of 12/6/84 is a copy of his review of EL DRAMA DE LES CAMELIES, O EL MAL QUE FA EL TEATRE by Jordi Teixidor.; Ivask, Ivar
  - World Literature Today. University of Oklahoma. Norman, Oklahoma., 1986-1987.; [3 of 3 folders] (Box 18)
    Also: Riggan, William; Ivask, Ivar
  - Yale College. New Haven, Connecticut., 1986. (Box 18)
  - Yale University. New Haven, Connecticut., 1938-1941. (Box 18)
  - Yale University. New Haven, Connecticut., 1986. (Box 18)
  - Yeshiva University. New York., 1984. (Box 18)
    Also: Serels, Mitchell
    Typescript(carbon) of Edouard Roditi's letter, 9 April 1984, to Mitchell Serels is included.
  - Yorck, Ruth., 1933-1963. (Box 18)
  - Young, Dana., 1976. (Box 18)
    One item is a printed page of poems by Dana Young and others.
  - Yourcenar, Marguerite., 1952-1955. (Box 18)
  - Yourcenar, Marguerite., 1986, n.d. (Box 18)
  - Zadkine, Ossip., 1949-1960. (Box 18)
    Two letters are in French.
  - Zafrani, Haim., 1974. (Box 18)
    Also: Department de Langue Hebraique et de Civilisation Juive. University de Paris VII. Paris.
    Typescript(carbon) of Edouard Roditi's letter, 22 June 1974, to Haim Zafrani is included. Photocopy of Haim Zafrani's letter to his colleagues is included.
  - Zendel, Gabriel., 1970-1974, n.d. (Box 18)
    Five postcards are undated. One item is a calling card with writing on it. These letters are in French.
  - Zerah, Tsilla Levy., 1981, n.d. (Box 18)
  - Zev., 1968-1972.; [1 of 3 folders] (Box 18)
  - Zev., 1972-1978.; [2 of 3 folders] (Box 18)
  - Zev., 1979-1981.; [3 of 3 folders] (Box 18)
    Enclosed with Zev's letter, 7 December 1981, to Edouard Roditi is a photograph of Zev.
  - Zev., 1960-1978.; [1 of 3 folders] (Box 18)
  - Zev., 1978-1987, n.d.; [2 of 3 folders] (Box 18)
  - Zev., n.d.; [3 of 3 folders] (Box 18)
    With ER's undated letter, coffee stained, is his article for PRISME, and a photocopy of the printed article, "Zev, et le genie comique."
  - Zimmermann, Mac., 1948. (Box 18)
  - Zlotnik, Alexandre., 1974. (Box 18)
    One item is a postcard. Alexandre Zlotnik's exhibition brochure with writing is included.
  - Zoete, Beryl de., n.d. (Box 18)
    Discussion on Edouard Roditi's book on Wilde.
  - Zukovsky, Louis., 1931. (Box 18)
  - Zumthor, Paul., 1979. (Box 18)
  - Zweig, Stefan., 1936. (Box 18)
  - Abraham, J.H., 1986. (Box 19)
  - Abrams, Sam., 1984. (Box 19)
  - Acker, David., 1984-1987, n.d. (Box 19)
  - Acts: A Journal of New Writing. San Francisco., 1988, n.d. (Box 19)
    Also: Hollander, Benjamin
  - Adrift. New York., 1985. (Box 19)
    Letter of 8/25/85 has photocopy of poem "Bulgaria" written by Thomas McGonigle in POETRY IRELAND REVIEW (No. 12).; McGonigle, Thomas
  - Aherdan, Majhoubi., 1979. (Box 19)
  - Akyavas, Erol., 1984, n.d. (Box 19)
  - Alcalay, Ammiel., 1986, n.d. (Box 19)
    Typescript of poem "Serious" enclosed with letter of 10/26/86.
  - Aleksic, Branko., 1988. (Box 19)
    Postcard from Boston postmarked 21 March 1988.
  - Alif. Cairo., 1988. (Box 19)
    Also: Ghazoul, Ferial J.
  - Alport, Eric., n.d. (Box 19)
  - American Book Review. New York., 1983. (Box 19)
  - American Scholar. Washington D.C., 1987. (Box 19)
    Carbon copy of letter dated 15 May 1987 regarding publication of a poem.
  - Anderson, Andrew A., 1987. (Box 19)
    Also: University of Michigan. Ann Arbor, Michigan.
  - Anderson-McQuoid, Patrick., 1986. (Box 19)
  - Annuaire de la Presse et de la Publicite. Paris., 1983. (Box 19)
    Form in French. Includes text regarding Edouard Roditi.
  - Ansen, Allen. (Box 19)
  - Antaeus. The Ecco Press. New York., 1986-1987. (Box 19)
  - Applefield, David., 1984-1987. (Box 19)
    Letter from Applefield to Madame Picot dated 31 juillet 1984 attached to letters from Edouard Roditi to Madame Picot dated 3 aout 1984 and photocopy of Centre National des Lettres' form about FRANK. Letter dated 24 September 1984 has two typed poems
  - Arajon, Shelomo., 1985. (Box 19)
  - Ararat. Saddle Brook, New Jersey., 1985-1987. (Box 19)
    Letter to Leo Hamalian from Corcoran Gallery of Art dated 15 February 1985 attached to letters from Roditi and manuscript about Ayvazovski. Letter to Leo Hamalian from the University of Michigan has Roditi's letter about Armen Lubin dated 10 March 1986.; Hamalian, Leo
  - Arban, Dominique., 1986, 1988. (Box 19)
  - Arion Press. San Francisco., 1987. (Box 19)
    Also: Hoyem, Andrew
    Letters from Edouard Roditi dated 28 March 1987 and 20 April 1987 carbon copies.
  - Arium Press. San Diego. (Box 19)
  - Arrizabalaga y Prado, Leonardo de., 1986-1989. (Box 19)
  - Art News. New York., October 1986. (Box 19)
    Letter dated 16 October 1986 has Edouard Roditi's article on the Nakhamkin Gallery exhibition of former Soviet artists from Paris.; Esterow, Milton
  - Arts & Antiques. New York., 1988. (Box 19)
  - Association des Artistes Peintres et Sculpteurs Juifs de France (APSJF). Paris., 1986. (Box 19)
    Letter in French.
  - Association Pour la Connaissance du Patrimoine Culturel Juif de France., n.d. (Box 19)
    Suggestions pour un sommaire.
  - Asylum. Greensboro, North Carolina., 1987-1988, n.d. (Box 19)
    Letter dated 9 December 1987 has copy of The head by Andree Chedid.
    Also: Boyd, Greg
    4 letters written on Asylum subscription advertisements.
  - Auden, W.H., 1931-1958. (Box 19)
    Typescript of No. 14 couplets with annotations by Auden and a biographical paragraph in Auden's hand with corrections by Roditi, noting that this was written for JOURNAL DES POETES.
    Postcard dated 9/2/58 to ER from Christine Tholsbey, with an added note to ER from Auden. 1 item is an undated note to "Christopher" [Isherwood ?] on Hotel Sevilia paper.
  - Aya Press. Toronto., 1983-1985. (Box 19)
    Letter from publisher dated 22 November 1984 has reviews of SHOE & SHIT, STORIES FOR PEDESTRIANS by Geoff Hancock and Rikki Ducornet from THE GLOBE AND MAIL (November 17, 1984) and THE TORONTO STAR (September 1, 1984).; Davies, Glynn
  - Bachem, Bele., 1978-1983. n.d. (Box 19)
    Includes photograph of statue, published reproduction of painting by Bachem, 2 postcards, and invitation to event on 21 October 1979. Correspondence in German.
  - Bak, Samuel., 1989. (Box 19)
  - Balakian, Anna., 1983-1987. (Box 19)
    Carbon copy of letter from Edouard Roditi dated 2 April 1987.
  - Balliol College. Oxford., 1988. (Box 19)
  - Bard College. Annandale-on-Hudson, New York., 1987-1988. (Box 19)
    Also: Levine, Stuart
  - Barozzi, Jacques., 1986. (Box 19)
  - Bedford Arts Publishers. San Francisco., 1988. (Box 19)
    Also: Vincent, Stephen
  - Bedford Press. San Francisco., 1987. (Box 19)
    Re proofs of Edouard Roditi's book, UNSUSPECTED GENIUS.
  - Begemann, Klaus-Dieter., 1983. (Box 19)
    Letter in German.
  - Behar, Henri., 1983, 1987. (Box 19)
  - Benkemoun., 1968-1985. (Box 19)
    Letter dated 14 December 1984 written back of photocopy of Roditi's article "Benkemoun et l'ecole Marocaine de lat peinture moderne" (1968).
    Photocopies of Edouard Roditi's article "Avec Cherkaoui, Belkahia, Benkemoun et L'ecole Marocaine de la peinture moderne," (1 October 1968), "Benkemoun," ARTS (12 October 1979), and "Benkemoun expose en France from le matine du Sahara," (9 Feb. 1981).
  - Black Sparrow Press. Santa Barbara, Calif., 1975-1988.; [1 of 2 folders] (Box 19)
    Also: Rissman, John
    With copy of Charles Bukowski's "Alone in a time of armies," (1985).
  - Black Sparrow Press. Santa Barbara, Calif., 1988.; [2 of 2 folders] (Box 19)
  - Blankertz, Stefan., n.d. (Box 19)
  - Blazer, Stuart., 1986, n.d. (Box 19)
  - Blot, Jean., 1985, 1989. (Box 19)
  - Boegehold, Alan L., 1987. (Box 19)
    Carbon copy of letter dated 29 April 1987 has copies of nine poems translated by Professor Alan L. Boegehold.; Brown University. Providence, Rhode Island.
  - Bokanowski, Helene., 1978. (Box 19)
  - Bosquet, Alain., 1985-1987, n.d. (Box 19)
    One postcard.
  - Botnick, Ken & Werner, Karen., 1982-1985. (Box 19)
    Also: Werner, Karen
    1985 card has poems by Botnick and Werner.
  - Bowles, Paul. (Box 19)
  - Brecht, Stefan., 1985-1987, n.d. (Box 19)
    Letter with envelope postmarked 27 July 1986 has copy of poem Codicil.
    2 postcards.
  - Brill, N.F., 1983-1984. (Box 19)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation. London., 1985. (Box 19)
    Also: Bumpus, Judith
    Includes talks requisition/contract dated 28 November 1985 signed by Edouard Roditi.
  - Broch de Rothermann, H.F., 1986-1987. (Box 19)
    Letter dated 12 April 1987 has copy of poem "Die waldlichtung "written by Hermann Broch in 1934 and translated by H.F. Broch de Rothermann. Letter also has copy of Hermann Broch's poem "La clairiere" translated by Edouard Roditi.
    Letters written in French.
  - Brook, Jim., 1988. (Box 19)
    Request for Edouard Roditi to write introduction for Jim Brook for PAJ Productions.
  - Broughton, James., 1984-1986, n.d. (Box 19)
    4 postcards. Letter written on back of advertisement for James Broughton's "Films erotiques et comiques" on 31 October.
  - Buffet, Annabel., 1986. (Box 19)
    Letter written in French.
  - Buot, Francois., 1988. (Box 19)
  - Burgess, Heather., 1987. (Box 19)
    Also: Ucross Foundation. Ucross, Wyoming.
  - Butscher, Edward., 1987. (Box 19)
    Also: Hofstra University. Hempstead, New York.
    Carbon copy of letter dated 23 May 1987.
  - McGraw-Hill Inc. New York., 1985. (Box 19)
    Also: Brutman, John
    Re rejection of MAGELLAN OF THE PACIFIC for publication.
  - Caballero, Luis., 1976, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Cadmus Editions. Tiburon-Belvedere, Calif., 1983-1984.; [1 of 7 folders] (Box 20)
    Also: Miller, Jeffrey
  - Cadmus Editions. Tiburon-Belvedere, Calif., 1984.; [2 of 7 folders] (Box 20)
  - Cadmus Editions. Tiburon-Belvedere, Calif., 1984-1985.; [3 of 7 folders] (Box 20)
  - Cadmus Editions. Tiburon-Belvedere, Calif., 1985-1986.; [4 of 7 folders] (Box 20)
    Also: Dino, Guzine
    With Jeffrey Miller's letter to ER, 7/2/89, copy of Guzine Dino's letter to Cadmus - 5/6/86, JM's reply 7/2/86, and note from GD to JM 8/8/86.; Miller, Jeffrey
  - Cadmus Editions. Tiburon-Belvedere, Calif., 1986-1987.; [5 of 7 folders] (Box 20)
  - Cadmus Editions. Tiburon-Belvedere, Calif., 1987-1988.; [6 of 7 folders] (Box 20)
    With Jeffrey Miller's letter, 10/30/87, is copy of letter from Farrar, Straus & Giroux, 10/16/87 re Lorca translations.; Miller, Jeffrey
  - Cadmus Editions. Tiburon-Belvedere, Calif., 1988.; [7 of 7 folders] (Box 20)
    With ER's letter of 5/4/88 is copy of cover piece for Patricia Eakin's THE HUNGRY GIRLS.
  - Caliban. Ann Arbor, Michigan., 1986-1987.; [1 of 2 folders] (Box 20)
    Also: Smith, Lawrence R.
  - Caliban. Ann Arbor, Michigan., 1987-1989.; [2 of 2 folders] (Box 20)
    With prospectus for CALIBAN 6.
  - Cameron, Esther., 1985. (Box 20)
    Poems entitled "In irons" (1971), "An invitation" (1975), "Unwritten poem" (15 December 1984), "Teshuva" (15 April 1985), and "In the mountains" (15 April 1985).
  - Camille, Georgette., 1986-1988, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Capra Press. Santa Barbara, Calif., 1974-1985. (Box 20)
    Also: Young, Noel
  - Carassou, Michel., 1981, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Carcanet New Press Limited. London., 1983. (Box 20)
  - Carmichael, Dr. and Mrs. W. F., 1987. (Box 20)
    Wedding announcement of Jill Carmichael and Dr. Giles H. Roditi.
  - Carmichael, Joel., 1986, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Carmo, Antonio., 1977, 1979. (Box 20)
    Newspaper clipping, n.d., "Antonio Carmo recria o real" and 3 photographs of Antonio Carmo's paintings.
  - Carruth, Hayden., 1983. (Box 20)
  - Casson, P., 1975-1976, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Castro, Jan., 1987. (Box 20)
  - Ceccatty, Rene de., 1985. (Box 20)
  - Champy Hatem, Madame., 1981. (Box 20)
  - Chedid, Andre., 1985, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Chill, Emanuel., 1987. (Box 20)
  - Cincinatti Historical Society. Cincinnati, Ohio., 1988. (Box 20)
  - Cioran, E.M., 1985-1988, n.d. (Box 20)
  - City Lights Booksellers & Publishers. San Francisco., 1988, n.d. (Box 20)
    Also: Sharrard, Bob
  - Clamshell Press. Santa Rosa., 1984. (Box 20)
    Also: Emblen, Don
  - Coffey, James T., 1984. (Box 20)
  - Cohen, Mitch., 1987-1989. (Box 20)
    Letter dated 4 March 1988 has computerized newsletter. With MC's letter of 2/15/89 is a letter from Deutscher Akademischer Austauschdients, Berlin.
    "`Seasons' and other greetings by Mitch Cohen: Haiku and senryu or things somewhat similar if counting's what counts."
  - Collection de L'Art Brut. Lausanne., 1986. (Box 20)
  - Columbia University. New York., 1987. (Box 20)
    Includes Edouard Roditi's letter of acceptance dated 6 February 1987.; Jemmott, Marion E.
    Re appointment and acceptance of adjunct professor of writing with the Faculty of the Arts.
  - Conference on Security and Co-operation in Europe. Belgrade., 1978. (Box 20)
  - Congregation Shearith Israel. New York., 1979, 1987. (Box 20)
    Also: Angel, Rabbi Marc D.
  - Conjunctions. New York., 1981.; [1 of 5 folders] (Box 20)
    Also: Morrow, Bradford
    1/81 - 7/81; 4 items - n.d.
  - Conjunctions. New York., 1981-1982.; [2 of 5 folders] (Box 20)
    With letter from ER to Bradford Morrow, 11/13/81, is copy of introduction to a Goytisolo essay.; Morrow, Bradford
    714/82 - 8/23/82.
  - Conjunctions. New York., 1982-1984.; [3 of 5 folders] (Box 20)
    With Bradford Morrow's letter of 2/18/83 are proofs of ER's Bunuel translations.
    8/23/82 - 7/13/84.
  - Conjunctions. New York., 1984-1987.; [4 of 5 folders] (Box 20)
    With letter from Bradford Morrow to ER, 7/28/84, is a form letter requesting funds for publication.; Morrow, Bradford
    7/28/84 - 6/15/87.
  - Conjunctions. New York., 1987-1988.; [5 of 5 folders] (Box 20)
    6/10/88 - 6/13/88.
  - Connolly, Cyril., 1946-1958, n.d. (Box 20)
    Letter dated 27 May 1958 has article written by Cyril Connolly from the SUNDAY TIMES, "Etty - the English Delacroix?" (18 May 1958).; Horizon. London.
  - Conway, John., 1986. (Box 20)
  - Copper Beech Press. Providence, Rhode Island., 1984. (Box 20)
  - Core. London., 1986. (Box 20)
    Also: Ceylan, Mevlut; Ferger, Feyyaz
  - Corso, Gregory., 1983-1986. (Box 20)
  - Crohmalniceanu, Ovid., 1978-1988. (Box 20)
  - Croxford, Leslie., 1987.; [4 of 5 folders] (Box 20)
    Also: American University of Cairo. Cairo.
  - Croxford, Leslie., 1988-1989.; [5 of 5 folders] (Box 20)
  - Crozier, Andrew., 1985. (Box 20)
    Also: Bridges Farmhouse
  - Dailey, William & Victoria., 1976-1986. (Box 20)
  - Dalkey Archive Press. Elmwood Park, Illinois., 1988. (Box 20)
    Also: O'Brien, John
  - De Roux, Jaqueline., 1986. (Box 20)
  - Delfiner, Henry., 1986. (Box 20)
  - Delirante. Paris., 1986-1987. (Box 20)
    Also: El-Etr, Fouad
  - Derus, Kenneth., 1988. (Box 20)
  - Dery, Mark., 1984-1985, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Design de Presse. Paris., 1987. (Box 20)
    Also: Wendygrad
  - Dibie, Isabelle., 1986. (Box 20)
    Also: Librairie Jose Corti. Paris.
  - Dino, Guzin., 1975-1986. (Box 20)
    Letter, 30 July 1986, has letter to Geoffrey Miller from Edouard Roditi, 6 August 1986.
  - Dissent. New York., 1985-1987. (Box 20)
  - Djerassi Foundation. Woodside, California., 1983-1986. (Box 20)
    Also: Djerassi, Carl; Learned-Driscoll, Susan
  - Dost Yayinlari. Istanbul., 1987-1988. (Box 20)
    Also: Sengil, Salim
  - E. P. Dutton. New York., 1987. (Box 21)
    Also: Marek, Richard
  - Eczacibasi, Shakir., 1985. (Box 21)
  - Editeurs d'Art Associes. Bruxelles., 1987-1988. (Box 21)
    Also: De Meyer, Lucien
  - Editions Claude Givaudan. Geneve and Paris., 1977. (Box 21)
  - Editions du Scribe. Paris., 1985-1986. (Box 21)
    Letter dated 16 September 1986 with copy of "Les artistes juifs originaires d'Algerie."
  - Editions Gallimard. Paris., 1985-1987. (Box 21)
    Also: Bergweiler, Ulrike; Guillou, Yannick
  - Eisenberg, Gary., 1985. (Box 21)
  - Elias' Modern Publishing House & Co. Cairo., 1985. (Box 21)
    Also: Elias, Eva
  - Emanuel, James A., 1987. (Box 21)
    Letter dated 13 July 1987 has James Emanuel's comments on Roditi's French translation of three poems while in New York.
  - Erikson, Buzz. (Box 21)
  - Eshleman, Clayton., 1985. (Box 21)
    Also: Sulfur. Los Angeles.
  - Europe. Paris., 1983-1987, n.d.; [1 of 2 folders] (Box 21)
  - Europe. Paris., 1987-1988, n.d.; [2 of 2 folders] (Box 21)
    With letter of 11/15/87 is "Bio-bibliographie of Hermann Broch," 9 p.
  - European Judaism. London., 1977-1978. (Box 21)
    Also: Friedlander, Albert H.; Marcus, Marcel
  - Farhi, Moris., 1987. (Box 21)
  - Farkas, Stephen J., Jr., 1988. (Box 21)
  - Feld, Hans., 1982. (Box 21)
  - Felstiner, John., 1988. (Box 21)
    Also: Stanford University. Palo Alto, Calif.
  - Felstiner, William., 1988. (Box 21)
  - Fergar, Feyyaz., 1987. (Box 21)